Preliminary Guide to the Alumni Affairs Records, 1851 - 2005 UA.14.01.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Alumni Affairs records
1851 - 2005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Office of Alumni Affairs
UA.14.01.0001
30 Linear Feet
The Office of Alumni Affairs at Duke University administers the Duke Alumni Association, a nonprofit organization serving over 120,000 alumni and former students of Duke University, in addition to thousands of parents and friends of the university. Records contain class files, administrative materials, fundraising materials, alumni publications records, subject files, photographs, video and sound recordings, and an index to Duke students who served in World War II. Materials include reunion information, correspondence, reports, programs, clippings, and printed matter. English.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Portions of these materials are restricted by donor request.
Unprocessed materials are closed pending processing.
Provenance
The Alumni Affairs Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1948-2002.
Historical Note
Since 1838, Duke University has had two locations and five name changes, but one of its oldest components has been an active alumni association. The Trinity College Alumni Association was founded in 1858 by President Braxton Craven, with forty-one alumni on record. In the 1890s, when the proposal to relocate Trinity College to Durham was announced, opposition to the plan was widespread among alumni. The Alumni Association, however, listened to the arguments for relocation with an open mind and decided to put the interests of "a greater Trinity" above personal considerations. In 1891, a year before the move, the College's charter was amended to require that one-third of its trustees be alumni of the College. This tenet remains a requirement of the University's bylaws today, twenty-seven of Duke's thirty-seven trustees are alumni, and five are past presidents of the Alumni Association.
Within a decade of the move to Durham, both men and women enrolled in dramatically increasing numbers from the North, the South, the Indian Territory (now Oklahoma) and abroad (especially Japan). Today's Duke Alumni Association represents more than 110,000 members from every state in the USA and more than seventy countries.
Just as the pool of alumni has dramatically grown and changed over the last 150 years, so has the role of the Alumni Association. From an association intended to foster friendships and maintain an ongoing affiliation between alumni and the university, the Alumni Association now also provides educational and travel opportunities, along with many university and community services. It disseminates information about university activities and issues to alumni and friends of the university, and produces its own sources of revenue to help support its programs.
These changing roles are expressions of an ongoing review by Alumni Association leadership and members of the alumni community. They illustrate the Alumni Association's ability to recognize the university's continually changing needs and its own opportunities to contribute to the Duke community.
[Historical note from http://dukealumni.com]
Collection Overview
Records contain class files, administrative materials, fundraising materials, alumni publications records, subject files, photographs, video and sound recordings, and an index to Duke students who served in World War II. Materials include reunion information, correspondence, reports, programs, clippings, and printed matter.
Related Material
Trinity College Alumni Association Records
University Archives, Duke University
Alumni Collections
University Archives, Duke University
Video recordings; World War, 1939-1945 -- Education and the war.; Photographs; Sound recordings; Duke University. Office of Alumni Affairs; Duke University. Alumni Association; Duke University -- Alumni and alumnae
- Class files, 1851-2005
  Scope and Contents note
  Missing Class of 1964, 1970, 1980, and 1981.
  - Class of 1851-1925 (Box Classes 1)
  - Class of 1926-1933 (Box Classes 2)
  - Class of 1934-1941 (Box Classes 3)
  - Class of 1942-1947 (Box Classes 4)
  - Class of 1948-1956 (Box Classes 5)
  - Class of 1957-1961 (Box Classes 6)
  - Class of Classes 1962-1965 (Box Classes 7)
  - Class of 1966-1969 (Box Classes 8)
  - Class of 1970-2005 (Box Classes 9)
- Administrative files
  - Director Henry Dwire records (Box 1)
  - Director Roger Marshall records
    - Memoranda (Box 1)
    - Alumni Admissions, 1960s and 1970s [A89-81.1] (Box 2)
    - Alumni Admissions, 1960s and 1970s [A89-81.2] (Box 3)
    - Alumni Trustees, Athletic Council, 1960s and 1970s [A89-81.3] (Box 4)
    - President's Office, Miscellaneous files, 1960s and 1970s [A89-81.4] (Box 5)
    - Commencement, general class files, 1960s and 1970s [A89-81.5] (Box 6)
    - Vigil and Allen Building Takeover files, 1968-1969 [A83-91] (Box 7)
  - Director's records, 1983-1993 [A96-39] (Box 8)
  - Vice President for Alumni Affairs and Development report, 1982/83-1983/84 [A87-6] (Box 9)
  - Assistant Director Anne Garrard records [A91-113, A92-28] (Box 10)
  - Reunion Director's records [A94-37] (Box 11)
  - Reunion Director mailings, 1990- (Box 12)
  - Ehle report, National Council records, 1974-1981 [A91-50, A91-51] (Box 13)
  - General Alumni Association National Council, ca. 1947-1974 [A98-6.1] (Box 14)
  - General Alumni Association National Council Executive Committee, ca. 1960s and 1970s [A98-6.2] (Box 15)
  - General Alumni Association National Council Executive Committee, ca. 1960s and 1970s [A98-6.3] (Box 16)
- Fundraising
  - Trinity College Memorial Gymnasium Fund pledge cards (Box 17)
  - Development and fundraising reports and handbooks (Box 18)
  - Loyalty Fund (Box 19)
  - Parents of students (Box 19)
  - Requests (Box 19)
- Publications
  - Publications Editor records [A91-2, A97-66, A2001-88, A2001-89, A2002-61] (Box 20)
  - Alumni Register records [A78-120] (Box 21)
  - Annual Reports (Box 22)
  - Alumni News, Alumni Newsletter (Box 22)
- Subject files
  - Alumni Association (Box 23)
    - General information (Box 23)
    - Elections (Box 23)
    - Office personnel (Box 23)
  - Alumni Memorial Scholarship Fund (Box 23)
  - Alumni Memorial Gymnasium (Box 23)
  - Sesquicentennial Celebration (Box 23)
  - Alumni Day (Box 24)
  - Commencement (Box 24)
  - Alumni Weekend, 1971-1985, 1999 (Box 24)
  - Alumni Council minutes (Box 25)
  - Alumni Secretary reports (Box 25)
  - Photographs (Box 25)
  - Alumni Clubs: DUBAC, States A-L (Box 26)
  - Alumni Clubs: States, M-W; International clubs (Box 27)
  - Half-Century Club (Box 28)
  - Alumnae Association [A77-217] (Box 29)
  - Medical School Alumni Association (Box 30)
  - Law School Alumni Association (Box 30)
  - Divinity School, Class files (Box 31)
  - Duke Experience Survey, 1985-1992 (Box 32)
  - Duke Experience Survey forms (Box 33)
  - Profile of the Class of 1968 survey, 1988 [A90-98] (Box 34)
  - Homecoming (Box 35)
  - Alumni Lecture Series (Box 35)
  - Saturday Seminars (Box 35)
  - Summer Institute (Box 35)
  - Social and athletic events (Box 35)
  - Athletic reunions (Box 35)
  - Sales and offers (Box 35)
  - Duke/Durham Alumni Association (Box 35)
  - Clippings (Box 35)
  - H. Keith H. Brodie, 1982-1989 (Box 35)
  - Louis Orr etchings information (Box 36)
  - Duke songs (Box 36)
  - Mailings to seniors (Box 36)
  - Duke anniversaries (Box 36)
  - Childress paintings (Box 36)
  - Events and programs: Travel (Box 37)
  - Events and programs: Travel (Box 38)
  - Oversized materials (Box 39)
- Non-print materials
  - Photographs [A91-7] (Box 40)
  - Video recordings, sound recordings, microforms (Box 41)
  - Motion pictures, video, sound recordings [A2000-78] (Box 42)
- World War II and military veteran alumni materials
  - Index of students who served in WWII: A-Br (Box 43, Index-box 1)
  - Index of students who served in WWII: Br-Dav (Box 43, Index-box 2)
  - Index of students who served in WWII: Dav-Geo (Box 43, Index-box 3)
  - Index of students who served in WWII: Ger-Hou (Box 43, Index-box 4)
  - Index of students who served in WWII: Hou-Len (Box 44, Index-box 5)
  - Index of students who served in WWII: Len-Moo (Box 44, Index-box 6)
  - Index of students who served in WWII: Moo-Rab (Box 44, Index-box 7)
  - Index of students who served in WWII: Rab-Smi (Box 44, Index-box 8)
  - Index of students who served in WWII: Smi-Wat (Oversize-box 45, Drawer 1)
  - Index of students who served in WWII: Wat-Deceased (Oversize-box 45, Drawer 2)
  - Alumni correspondence about WWII, 2008-2009; 4 folders (Box 48)
  - World War II and Duke research, 1942-1949, 2008 (Box 48)
  - David M. Dean letter and materials regarding alumni killed during Vietnam War, 2009 (Box 48)